[{
       "question":"Core of Linux Operating system is________" ,
       "choice1":"Shell" ,
       "choice2":"Kernel" ,
       "choice3": "Terminal",
       "choice4":"Command" ,
       "answer":2

},
   {   
      "question":"Which is the default file system type of Linux?",
      "choice1":"ext",
      "choice2":"ext2",
      "choice3":"etx3",
      "choice4": "mimix",
      "answer":3
},
{
     "question":"What command is used to count the total number of lines,words and characters contained in a file?",
      "choice1":"wc",
      "choice2":"count w",
      "choice3":"wcount",
      "choice4": "count p",
      "answer":1
},
{
     "question":"Hidden file can be viewed using______",
     " choice1":"ls -l",
     " choice2":"ls -a",
     " choice3":"ls -h",
     " choice4": "ls -k",
     " answer":2
},
{
    "question":"Which is the correct command and syntax to rename a file 'abc.txt' to 'pqr.txt'?",
      "choice1":"mv pqr.txt abc.txt",
      "choice2":"mv -a pqr.txt abc.txt",
      "choice3":"mv abc.txt pqr.txt",
      "choice4": "mv -all pqr.txt abc.txt",
      "answer":3
},
{
    "question":"Which linux command is used to display the content of file?",
      "choice1":"display",
      "choice2":"show",
      "choice3":"echo",
      "choice4": "cat",
      "answer":2
},
{
    "question":"Which command is used for changing the current directory?" ,
       "choice1":"cd" ,
       "choice2":"cp" ,
       "choice3": "pwd",
       "choice4":"None of these" ,
       "answer":1
},
   {
     "question":"The sudo coomand stands for?" ,
       "choice1":"su" ,
       "choice2":"superuser does" ,
       "choice3": "superuser do",
       "choice4":"super do" ,
       "answer":3
},
 {
     "question":"Which command is used to display the unix version?" ,
       "choice1":"kernel" ,
       "choice2":"uname -n" ,
       "choice3": "uname -t",
       "choice4":"uname -r" ,
       "answer":4
},
{
    "question":"To make a pipe,put a ______ on the command line between two commands?" ,
       "choice1":"|" ,
       "choice2":"/" ,
       "choice3": "\n",
       "choice4":"$" ,
       "answer":1
}]